Susan Caperna Lloyd collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 12: Basque culture, 1 folder
  - Portfolio 10: Basque Folk Festival, 1996, The photographs in this portfolio were made in July, 1996 during the annual Elko, Nevada Basque Festival. Participants and attendees at the festival came from Nevada, the surrounding western states and the Pyrenees in Spain from where many western U.S. Basque originated. The Basque, besides possessing one of the world's oldest languages, pride themselves in skills such as woodcutting, world-class weight lifting, sheepherding, folk dancing, and games such as jai lai and bertsolari, a verse competition. They brought these skills with them when many migrated to the U.S. western states in the 1920s to work in the sheep industry. So that the skills wouldn't be forgotten, the Basque perform traditional dances and stage wood chopping and weightlifting competitions at festivals that are also held in the old country, a tradition since the 19th century. Although few Basque in the U.S. are sheepherders anymore, participants in the festivals, ranging from California to Colorado, show off their herd dogs and Basque families come to hear stories from the old-timers.; 1 portfolio (12 photographs): color Ultrachrome archival inkjet prints; 13 x 19 inch (Box 52)
    - Print 1: Flock of Pete Borda's sheep, Minden, Nevada, AFC 2018/064: PH0118
    - Print 2: Domingo Aguirre, sheepherder, Elko, Nevada Basque Festival, AFC 2018/064: PH0103
    - Print 3: Basque boy with bota bag, Elko, Nevada Basque Festival, AFC 2018/064: PH0129
    - Print 4: Basque man distributing wine, Elko, Nevada Basque Festival, AFC 2018/064: PH0113
    - Print 5: Young Basque jota dancer, Elko, Nevada Basque Festival, AFC 2018/064: PH0109
    - Print 6: Man in "Basque and Proud of It" shirt, Elko, Nevada Basque Festival, AFC 2018/064: PH0126
    - Print 7: Christine Saralegi (from Navarra, Spain), wood chopping champion, Elko, Nevada, Basque Festival, AFC 2018/064: PH0119
    - Print 8: Weight-lifting six hundred pound steel block, Elko, Nevada Basque Festival, AFC 2018/064: PH0104
    - Print 9: Brokel-dantza hoop dance, Elko, Nevada Basque Festival, AFC 2018/064: PH0110
    - Print 10: Brokel-dantza hoop dance, Elko Nevada, Basque Festival, Elko, AFC 2018/064: PH0102
    - Print 11: Young Basque boys with bota bags, Elko, Nevada Basque Festival, AFC 2018/064: PH0112
    - Print 12: Sheepherders' trailer on the outskirts of Elko, Nevada. Elko, Nevada Basque Festival, AFC 2018/064: PH0120
  - [Basque culture], 1997, Manuscripts and ephemera related to Basque culture in Nevada.; 1 folder (Box/folder 33/2)
  - Basque country, Spain notebook, March 1998, Research notes for film on Basque folk culture: San Sebastian, Gernika, Pamplona bull runners, bertsolari verse competition, Gernika legends, Chillida's sculpture, sheepherder countryside and culture.; 1 notebook (Box/folder 33/3)
  - Seville, Spain, 1998, AFC 2018/064: SL-15-04; 41 black-and-white negatives (35 mm); Spain (Basque); Kodak (Box 21)
- Series 13: Cuba
  - Legacy of Che Guevara, folk hero, Cuba, 1998, AFC 2018/064: PH0281-PH0320; 40 color slides (35 mm); 281-282, Santiago, Cuban southern coast; 283, Fort Santiago; 284, Santiago Harbor; 285-286, Sierra Maestra range, cradle of Cuban Revolution; 287, Depiction of Che Guevara on horseback, Santa Clara Memorial; 288, Sierra Maestra range; 289, "Ever Onward Until Victory," Che Guevara billboard; 290, Farmer in cart on road in Santiago; 291-292, Veterans of Cuban Revolution and Congo, Santiago; 293-295, Che Guevara mausoleum, Santa Clara; 296-298, Cuban Revolution mural, Santa Clara Memorial; 299, Santa Clara Hotel, Cuban Revolution battle site, Santa Clara; 300, Veteran of Cuban Revolution, Santa Clara; 301, "Queremos que sean como el Che" sign, Santa Clara; 302, Sculpture of Guevara/Cienfuegos, Museum of Revolution, Havana; 303, Display in Museum of Revolution, Havana; 304, Graffiti about imperialism and Yankees, Havana; 305, Forty second anniversary of Revolution sign; 306, Perfume and Che Guevara postcards for sale, Havana; 307, Che Guevara display, Santa Clara; 308, Folk hero Antonio Maceo sign; 309, Plaza of the Revolution, Che Guevara installation, Havana; 310-311, Che Guevara mosaic; 312, T-shirt "Havana to Harlem Same Struggle," Havana; 313, Veterans of Cuban Revolution, Santiago; 314, Portrait of Che Guevara, Havana restaurant; 315, Truckload of Cuban Police, Santiago; 316, Sign "Hasta la victoria siempre," Santiago; 317, Che Guevara billboard, Matanzas; 318, Museum of the Revolution exhibit, 26 de Julio tank, Havana; 319, Farmer on horseback with machete, Santiago; 320, Sign "Revolucion victoriosa en el nuevo milenio," Havana. (Box 2)
  - Cuba, 1998, AFC 2018/064: PH0321-PH0340; 20 color slides (35 mm); 321-322, Havana harbor; 323, Embargo reduced variety of merchandise, Havana; 324, Dilapidated hospital waiting room, Santiago; 325, Hospital patient in bed; 326, Blood dispensary in hospital; 327-331, Unrestored vintage cars in Havana; 332, Farmer on horse-drawn cart, Santiago; 333, Afro-Cuban child in pinafore, Havana; 334, Cuban baseball team members, Santiago; 335, Portrait of a Cuban girl in garden, Havana; 336, Burning sugar cane; 337, Cuban architecture, Santa Clara; 338, School children, central Cuba; 339, Children walking home carrying their shoes, rural Cuba; 340, Street scene, Havana. (Box 2)
  - Portfolio 12: Legacy of Che Guevara, Folk Hero, 1998, Ernesto "Che" Guevara, born in Argentina and trained as a doctor, was a revolutionary hero who co-led the Cuban Revolution (July 26, 1953-January 1, 1959) with Fidel Castro. Beginning in the Sierra Maestra, they led their rag-tag army out of the mountains, took the city of Santa Clara and entered Havana victoriously, overthrowing the Batista government. The new socialist government of Fidel and Che was a dream experiment. The Cubans, the majority of whom were peasants and disenfranchised by years of oppressive governments, embraced the Revolution. Che, who led another uprising in the Congo and a failed revolution in Bolivia where he died in 1967, became a folk hero over the ensuing decades. For many years his body was not found, giving rise to a belief by some that he did not die. Others cited the brave way in which he faced his captors in Vallegrande when he was shot at age forty-one. His portrait became an iconic image still seen throughout Cuba and Argentina today. The photographs in this portfolio were taken in 1998 when combatants who fought with him still wore his iconic beret or displayed photographs of him in their homes; schoolchildren walked home barefoot from school to save shoe leather and follow Che's example; billboards throughout Cuba declared: "We want to be like Che." Guevara follows the model of the folk hero who dies before one's time. The folk are then left with the hope that he can "return" and the dream restored-that the ideals of the Revolution will endure.; 1 portfolio (10 photographs); color Ultrachrome archival inkjet prints; 19 x 13 inch (Box 54)
    - Print 1: Santiago and Sierra Maestra range, Cuban southern coast, AFC 2018/064: PH0282
    - Print 2: Veteran of Cuban Revolution, Santa Clara, Cuba, AFC 2018/064: PH0300
    - Print 3: Che Guevara billboard ("In His Example"). Matanzas, Cuba, AFC 2018/064: PH0317
    - Print 4: Veterans of Cuban Revolution & Congo, Santiago, Cuba, AFC 2018/064: PH0291
    - Print 5: T-shirt "Havana to Harlem Same Struggle," referencing Fidel Castro's 1959 visit to the U.S. Havana, Cuba, AFC 2018/064: PH0312
    - Print 6: "Ever Onward Until Victory," Che Guevara billboard, Cuba, AFC 2018/064: PH0289
    - Print 7: Portrait of Che Guevara, Havana restaurant, Cuba, AFC 2018/064: PH0314
    - Print 8: "Queremos que sean como el Che" (We want them to be like Che) sign at Guevara memorial, Santa Clara, Cuba, AFC 2018/064: PH0301
    - Print 9: Eduardo Labrada, Veteran of Cuban Revolution, Manzanillo, Cuba, AFC 2018/064: PH0292
    - Print 10: School children walking home carrying their shoes, rural Cuba, AFC 2018/064: PH0339
  - Cuba, 1998-2001, 1 folder (Box/folder 34/1)
    - Interview with doctor at Santiago, Cuba hospital. Also letter from Cuban friend, Yoander, expressing appreciation for Lloyd's interest in Cuba and its iconic heroes. Also photos of Susan Lloyd wearing beret popularized by Che Guevara and singing Guantanamera at Havana restaurant. Other photograph of Lloyd in front of Che Guevara painting, April 1998, See AFC 2018/064: PH0324-PH0326.; AFC 2018/064: H-01
    - Newspaper interview with Susan Lloyd about Cuba, The Mail Tribune (Medford, Oregon), August 17, 2001, See AFC 2018/064: PH0281-PH0340.; AFC 2018/064: H-02
  - Yaquis, Tucson; Cuba; Yaquis, Hermosillo; and New Mexico notebook, 1999-2004, 1 notebook (Box/folder 29/4)
- Series 14: Afghanistan
  - Bamiyan Buddhas, September 2005, afc2018064_dc001; 1-6, Two sixth century monumental Buddhas stood in niches in Bamiyan as Afghanistan was a thriving Buddhist center until the seventh century Islamic invasion. In 2001, the Taliban blew them up but with Chinese help the Buddhas were recreated in 2015 by holographic light projection.; 6 still image files (jpg)
  - Women in burqa, September 2005, afc2018064_dc001; 1-26, Women in burqas on Kabul streets. The blue coverings were mandatory under Taliban rule but traditionally many women prefer wearing them for protection from stares or to inversely look at whatever they want to without being observed.; 26 still image files (jpg)
  - Afghan countryside, September 2005, afc2018064_dc001; 1-3, 51, 55-62, Donkeys carry hay on road to Lake Bandi Amir; 4, 15-17, 20, 22-24, 52-54, 68-75, 78-80, Relics such as tanks and trucks from the Soviet-Afghan War are scattered throughout the countryside; 5-9, 11, 13-14, 18-19, 21, 33-34, 44, 65, North central Afghanistan landscape; 10, Harvesting fields; 12, 25, Harvesting with oxen; 26-27, Autumn harvest fields; 28, 31, 35, 37-39, 41, 82, Traditional Pakistani decorated truck near Jalalabad; 29, Woman in burqa on country road; 30, 40, Kuchi nomads on the road near Kabul; 32, 36, Road from Kabul to Jalalabad; 42-43, ISAF forces on road to Jalalabad; 45, Boy at roadside inn; 46, Susan Lloyd's traveling companions; 47-48, Feed barn in north central Afghanistan; 49-50, Woman with hands decorated with henna; 63-64, Hazara woman at Lake Bandi Amir; 66-67, ISAF forces near Bamiyan; 76-77, Door detail; 81, Road to Jalalabad.; 82 still image files (jpg)
  - Parliamentary elections, September 2005, afc2018064_dc001; 1, 4-12, 16, 22-25, 30-31, 34-37, 43, 45-47, 61-65, 68-69, 72-87, 89, 91-92, 96-108, Election voting center; 2-3, 15, 17-19, 26, 28-29, 33, 38-42, 44, 48-51, 53-54, 56-60, 67, Election campaigning and posters; 13-14, 32, Elections; 20-21, 27, 70-71, 88, 93-95, Afghan police safeguarding elections; 52, Najibullah Sedeqe was the guide for the Global Exchange group visiting Kabul to help monitor the 2005 Parliamentary elections; 55, Election poster; 66, Parliamentary elections; 90, Najibullah Sedeqe voting at election voting center.; 108 still image files (jpg)
  - Food culture, September 2005, afc2018064_dc001; 1, Spices in Kabul market shop; 2, Street kabobs; 3-9, 15-16, Eating traditionally upon mats rolled out on the floor; 10, Soviet tea samovar in Kabul; 11-13, Naan bread baking; 14, Teapots awaiting customers in countryside inn; 17-20, Kitchen in countryside.; 20 still image files (jpg)
  - Hazaras, September 2005, afc2018064_dc001; 1-4, Hazara woman holding photo of deceased husband killed in the 2001 U.S. aerial bombing. Her name is Arafa and she lives with her three children in her destroyed house awaiting government aid. After the bombing she found her husband's body rolled up in a carpet; 5-6, Hazara boy in Kabul. Since the Shia Hazara live in predominately Sunni Afghanistan they face cultural and economic discrimination as well as religious persecution; 7-14, Susan Lloyd with Hazara man wounded in Taliban bomb attack during 2005 Parliamentary elections.; 14 still image files (jpg)
  - Hospitals, September 2005, afc2018064_dc001; 1-6, Artificial limbs are made for land mine victims at the Kabul Red Cross land mine hospital; 7, Foot of Afghan National Army victim of bomb attack during 2005 Parliamentary elections, at Sardar Mohammad Dawood Khan Hospital; 8-14, 24-25, Afghan National Army victim of bomb attack during 2005 Parliamentary elections, at Sardar Mohammad Dawood Khan Hospital; 15-22, 28-29, Blinded and captured member of Taliban treated in Kabul hospital. Doctors didn't know his name and said he had no shoes even though he would soon be released; 23, Fellow soldiers visit Afghan National Army victims of bomb attacks during 2005 Parliamentary elections; 26-27, Hospital nurse.; 29 still image files (jpg)
  - Kuchi nomads, September 2005, afc2018064_dc001; 1-7, Kuchi nomad children. The Kuchis live in temporary tent camps with their sheep and do not participate in Afghanistan's politics.; 7 still image files (jpg)
  - Legacy of folk hero Massoud, September 2005, afc2018064_dc001; 1-4, Posters of Massoud; 5, 10-21, 25-26, 39, 69, 73-74, Images large and small of Ahmed Shah Massoud are everywhere in Afghanistan. Massoud led the Tajiks to successfully defeat the Soviets and was instrumental in defeating the Taliban until he was assassinated in 2001; 6-9, Fahim Dashti, Kabul weekly newspaper editor wounded by bombing blast which killed Massoud; 22, 24, 32, 40-42, Tawakal Khan, he was Massoud's bodyguard and was blinded in the bomb attack when Massoud was killed; 23, 30-31, Tawal Khan and Habib Wafa, they are Tajiks. Tawakal was Massoud's bodyguard when he was killed and Tawakal was blinded. Habib is his friend and a Kabul journalist; 26-29, The tomb of Massoud near his home in the Panjshir in 2005. At this time a three story Islamic tower in stone was beginning to be built around it; 33-36, 46-48, 55-56, 65, 75, Everyone in the Panjshir considers themselves a mujahid which is a guerilla fighter in an Islamic country. Under the leadership of Massoud the Tajik mujahideen fought against the Taliban but not as jihadists; 37-38, 49-50, 57-60, Relics captured by Massoud's forces during the Soviet-Afghan War dot the Panjshir Valley; 43-45, Massoud's home in the Panjshir; 51-54, Susan Lloyd interviews Tawakal Khan on tank captured by Massoud's forces in the Panjshir during the Soviet-Afghan War; 61-64, The shoes of Massoud which are kept where he left them on the floor of the backseat of his Cygnus SUV; 66-68, Prayer rug and rifle belonging to Massoud. They are kept where Massoud left them in the back of his Cygnus and are watched over by the mujahideen; 70-72, 76-78, Massoud's Cygnus SUV in the Panjshir. The mujahideen guard it and Massoud's personal effects which are inside; 79-80, Mountains of the Panjshir which was Massoud's home and where he is buried; 81, Entrance to the Panjshir Valley and billboard of Massoud.; 81 still image files (jpg)
  - Kabul school life, September 2005, afc2018064_dc001; 1, 6, 39-50, 54-56, Afghans for Tomorrow backpack and supplies delivery to a Kabul school. Donated by Southeast Denver Rotary Club; 2-5, 7-14, 17-23, 26, 28-30, 33-38, 51-53, 58, School children; 15-16, 24-25, School lessons; 27, 57, School teacher; 31, School bulletin board; 32, Heart prayer to Allah in Arabic calligraphy.; 58 still image files (jpg)
  - Kabul street scenes, September 2005, afc2018064_dc001; 1-3, Shoe shine boy; 4, Army equipment for sale; 5, Kabul police officer in his tent on street; 6, Boy with traditional kite string spool; 7-9, 11-12, 15, 17, Kabul street portrait; 10, Afghan dog; 13, Shop sign; 14, Street photographer's portable darkroom; 16, Backyard of Global Exchange guest house; 18, International Security Assistance Force guards site of bomb attack; 19-20, Antique shop; 21, International Hotel; 22-24, Injured woman covered in traditional robe; 25-26, Taking down Pashtun shop sign.; 26 still image files (jpg)
  - Afghanistan (1 of 2), 2005, 1 folder (Box/folder 33/4)
    - Voice of the Mujahadeen newspaper about folk hero Ahmad Shah Massoud, an Afghan Tajik who led forces to defeat the Russians in the Soviet-Russian War. He was killed in a bomb attack by al-Qaeda operatives and became mythic, his photo everywhere in Afghanistan. Published in English in Kabul, Afghanistan, See AFC 2018/064: PH0241-PH0260 for images of Massoud, his gravesite, and the Tajiks in the Panjshir Valley.; AFC 2018/064: J-01
    - Miscellaneous newspapers covering Parliamentary elections in Afghanistan, AFC 2018/064: J-02
    - Global Exchange itinerary. This is the host group that Susan Lloyd travelled with in Afghanistan, AFC 2018/064: J-03
  - Afghanistan (2 of 2), 2005, 1 folder (Box/folder 33/5)
    - Press credentials for Susan Lloyd observing polling in Kabul during Parliamentary elections in Afghanistan, AFC 2018/064: J-04
    - Receipt for guest for twelve days at Afghans For Tomorrow Guest House, Kabul, Afghanistan, September 27, 2005, AFC 2018/064: J-05
    - Newspaper article by Susan Lloyd Blinded in a Forgotten War with photo, Ashland Daily Tidings, page A8, See AFC 2018/064: PH0141-PH0280.; AFC 2018/064: J-06
    - Newspaper article by Susan Lloyd In Afghanistan with an Ashland Marine with photo, Ashland Daily Tidings, October 10, 2005, See AFC 2018/064: PH0141-PH0280.; AFC 2018/064: J-07
    - Newspaper article, How Do You Say 'Please Don't Shoot Me,' in Pashtun? in the Mail Tribune, about Susan Lloyd's forthcoming trip to Afghanistan, September 16, 2005, AFC 2018/064: J-08
  - [Afghanistan], 2005, 1 folder (Box/folder 33/6)
  - Afghan book notes, 2005, Mainly notes made in Kabul about possible book/memoir about Afghanistan. Lloyd's son was there and she came over as a reporter and toured the country at a dangerous time post-9-11.; 1 notebook (Box/folder 33/7)
  - Afghanistan notebooks (1 of 3), 2005, Notes about digital camera used in Afghanistan, sending articles digitally to U.S. news outlets and laptop issues, data from rocket attacks after parliamentary elections, Kabul "to do" list, flight itineraries, Pakistan Daily Times articles on parliamentary elections, notes from Masuda Jalala conversation, Ministry of Women's' Affairs, Kabul. Notes made about Panshir Valley and Tajiks, Ramadan, wounded Taliban, notes with Ministry of Defense, U.S. intelligence agent, Gul Chan notes.; 2 notebooks (Box/folder 33/8)
  - Afghanistan notebooks (2 of 3), 2005, Notes, interviews Afghanistan.; 2 notebooks (Box/folder 33/9)
  - Afghanistan notebooks (3 of 3), 2005, Notes, interviews Afghanistan.; 1 notebook (Box/folder 33/10)
  - Hazara civilian bombing survivors in Kabul, Afghanistan, 2005, AFC 2018/064: PH0141-PH0168; 28 color slides (35 mm); 141-144, Arafa with photos of dead husband and son, killed when her house was bombed; 145-148, Father and daughter waiting for tea; 149-160, Saheb Dad family living in bomb damaged house; 161-168, Family outside bombed house. (Box 1)
  - Hazara civilian bombing survivors in Kabul, Afghanistan, 2005, AFC 2018/064: PH0169-PH0180; 12 color slides (35 mm); 169-175, Women cooking outside bombed houses; 176, Boy in bombed out doorway; 177-180, Green flags mark graves of bombing victims. (Box 2)
  - Buddhas of Bamiyan dynamited and destroyed by the Taliban, Afghanistan, 2005, AFC 2018/064: PH0181-PH0200; 20 color slides (35 mm); 181, View of cliffs and valley; 182, Road along Bamiyan, Afghanistan cliffs; 183, Detail of bombed bazaar; 184, Women on road alongside cliffs; 185, UNESCO sign in front of destroyed Buddha niche; 186-187, United Nations excavators at main Buddha niche; 188-189, Caves on Bamiyan Valley cliff wall; 190, Niche of obliterated Buddha; 191, Stairway inside the cliff wall leading to monasteries and sanctuaries; 192, Niches with graffiti, inner sanctuary inside cliff wall; 193, Inner sanctuary with restoration equipment; 194, Graffiti in inner sanctuary; 195, View of Bamiyan Valley from within bombed Buddha niche; 196, View of ground below from within bombed Buddha niche; 197, View of Bamiyan Valley from within bombed Buddha niche; 198-199, Restoration workers; 200, Donkey and local guides overlooking Bamiyan Valley. (Box 2)
  - Kuchi nomad encampment near Kabul, Afghanistan, 2005, AFC 2018/064: PH0201-PH0216; 16 color slides (35 mm); 201-204, Feeding camels; 205-206, Folk art textiles decorate camels; 207-210, In-ground cooking and boiling water for tea; 211-213, Children in Kuchi encampment; 214-216, Children with decorated sheep in Kuchi encampment. (Box 2)
  - Internally displaced persons' camp, Kabul, Afghanistan, 2005, AFC 2018/064: PH0217-PH0220; 4 color slides (35 mm); 217, Internally displaced persons mothers and family; 218-220, Children in internally displaced persons camp. (Box 2)
  - Afghanistan land-mine victims at Red Cross Center, Kabul, 2005, AFC 2018/064: PH0221-PH0240; 20 color slides (35 mm); 221-231, Doctor fitting limb to victim; 232-236, Patients waiting for doctors; 237-239, Three-year old boy walking on artificial legs for first time; 240, Teen walking on artificial legs. (Box 2)
  - Ahmad Shah Massoud, Tajik folk hero, Panjshir, Afghanistan, 2005, AFC 2018/064: PH0241-PH0260; 20 color slides (35 mm); 241, Portrait of Massoud over gateway to Panjshir Valley; 242-243, Panjshir mountain landscape; 244, Site of Massoud's tomb; 245, Susan Lloyd interviews Tawakal Khan Mujahid, body guard of Massoud; 246, Tawakal Khan, bodyguard of Massoud; 247, Tajik men having tea; 248, Tajik Mujahideen holding book about Massoud; 249, Tajik Mujahideen; 250, Driving through a Panjshir village; 251, Mujahideen and journalist in front of Massoud home in Panjshir Valley; 252, Mujahideen in front of Massoud home in Panjshir Valley; 253, Detail of Massoud compound; 254, Susan Lloyd seated at Massoud home; 255, Panjshir Valley landscape; 256, Islamic mosque; 257-258, Highway billboard of Massoud outside Kabul; 259, Soviet tanks on Shomali Plain destroyed by Massoud forces during 1979 war; 260, Panjshir Valley at dusk. (Box 2)
  - Afghanistan, 2005, AFC 2018/064: PH0261-PH0280; 20 color slides (35 mm); 261, Hazara couple, Kabul; 262, Hazara children, Kabul; 263, Taekwondo, Kabul; 264, Woman on road, Bamiyan Valley; 265, Decorated truck, Jalalabad; 266-267, Afghan girl's feet and sandals, Panjshir Valley; 268, Hazara children, Kabul; 269-271, Tajik girl, Panjshir Valley; 272, Tajik boys and goat, Panjshir Valley; 273-275, Afghan boys and father with bird cage, Kabul; 276, Afghan bird cage, Kabul; 277, Afghan cooking pots, Bamiyan Valley; 278, Afghan boys on soccer field, Kabul; 279, Hands of Hazara woman holding baby, Kabul; 280, Hazara children, Kabul. (Box 2)
- Series 15: Turkey
  - Ankara, October 2006, afc2018064_dc001; 1, Equestrian statue of Kemal Ataturk who was the founder of modern Turkey; 2-3, Mausoleum of Kemal Ataturk who was the founder of modern Turkey; 4, Statue group at mausoleum of Kemal Ataturk who was the founder of modern Turkey; 5-7, Ankara mosque; 8, Ankara market with traditional feminine headscarves. They are controversial and banned in the workplace to counter conservatism while other societal factions fight to wear them; 9-20, Roman statues at Ankara Museum of Anatolian Civilizations.; 20 still image files (jpg)
  - Cappadocia, October 2006, afc2018064_dc001; 1, 4-27, The Cappadocia region contains cave homes and rock cut churches and monasteries built from 300-1200 A.D.; 2-3, Turkish cooking pots.; 27 still image files (jpg)
  - Catal Huyuk, October 2006, afc2018064_dc001; 1-2, 7, Habitation at Neolithic site of Catal Huyuk; 3-5, Geometric ochre wall painting in habitation at Catal Huyuk which flourished as a shared society; 6, Rafters of habitation at Catal Huyuk with hanging dried herbs; 8, Excavation site at Catal Huyuk.; 8 still image files (jpg)